# ANTHONY SCARDINO

#### **CONTACT**

267-251-2746 a.scardino@gmail.com

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Esri Suite of Products

- ArcPro
- ArcServer
- · Image Server
- · Portal/AGOL

Computer Languages

- Python
- HTML
- XML for Metadata
- SQL
- JavaScript

Azure Cloud Services

Databricks

CompTIA Sec+

Jira for Agile Management

#### **SOFT SKILLS**

Over 7 years of Supervisory and Mentorship experience

5 years of Project Management experience

#### **PROFILE**

Anthony has 17 years of experience, providing creative solutions for a variety of federal and private projects. He has been nominated for Employee of the Year in three successive years.

Anthony is a former member of the Navy Region Mid-Atlantic Crisis
Activation Team and Threat Working Group. He brings extensive training
experience, including leading a group for over two months in offshore
location of Pune, India integrating and training staff. In addition to managing
projects and solution deployment, he is a supervisor and mentor, managing
five coworkers. He is a Lead of the Supervisors' Community of Practice.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Solutions Architect, GISinc, Axim purchased by NV5 — 2012 - Present

Manages the implementation and sustainment of multiple Enterprise solutions, through Development Lifecycle, across multiple clients. Performs automation of data manipulation through Python and APIs. Creates solutions via customization, development within Esri ecosystem.

#### United States Air Force, Air Mobility Command — 2019 - Present

- Acting part of AWS Cloud Deployment Team.
- Responsible for technical requirements analysis, development of innovative applications using javascript or out of the box solutions hosted in Portal for ArcGIS.
- Provide subject matter expertise in new software versioning updates, additions, DevOps cycle.
- Responded to multiple emergency scenarios. Created dashboarding applications for multiple planning exercises.

#### United States Navy, GeoReadiness Enterprise Systems (GES) - 2014 - Present

- Part of Cloud Deployment Team migrating GES into Microsoft Azure IL4.
- Led implementation of enterprise-wide Image Services; continue to lead on-going optimization in Azure Cloud.
- Serving as subject matter expert for hosting, accessing approx. 1 Petabyte of data within Azure Cloud.
- Responsible for requirements gathering through to deployment and ongoing optimization of Navy's Flood Inundation and Storm Hazards application.

#### City of Houston, Emergency Management Department — 2019

• Worked with City of Houston officials to create applications for event planning and Traffic Incident management.

# United States Navy, Mid-Atlantic Regional Operations Center – 2012 - 2014

- Responsible for location based situational awareness during and in preparation for emergencies.
- Responded to multiple emergencies, including the Boston Bombing Terrorist attack.
- Member of the Threat Working Group and Crisis Activation Team.

# Lead Geographer FEMA Region III Regional Support Center, Dewberry — 2008 - 2012

- Dewberry Spotlight Award for exceeding commitment during contract acquisition. Acted as MIP Black Belt; a liaison between FEMA's Clients and the MIP, their project tracking and management platform.
- Supported Hazard Mitigation officers in FEMA Joint Field Office for post disaster relief in Pennsylvania.

#### **EDUCATION**

Pennsylvania State University — Bachelor of Science, Geography, 2005

## WHAT OTHERS ARE SAYING ABOUT ANTHONY:

#### **Employee Owner of The Year Nominations:**

"While managing these projects he never fails to boost morale with his coworkers and supervisees, whether it be through his outreach [...] or his efforts to help others find their path at GISinc. [now NV5]"

"Anthony is a go-getter and always positive while taking on any challenge and making the most of it, and it seems he keeps getting some of the most difficult projects to manage."

# Coworker Chris, within Company-wide Communications:

"[...] every time we work together, he makes me better. Thank you for showing me the value of patience and listening. You are immeasurable, but so impactful to our success."

## Coworker Heather, within Company-wide Communications:

"Anthony Scardino is the rebar in the foundation of many Federal GIS programs and AMC is no exception. We recently had a database server migration [...] and his attention to details ensured a smooth transition. I would not be able to do my job effectively without Anthony's support on my team."